# **Matteo Pellegrino**

I am a product-oriented Web Software Engineer specialized in full-stack development for scale-ups. I profoundly care about business impact as well as UX & UI while keenly nerding on the software architecture and technical details. I thoroughly enjoy bootstrapping and scaling up digital products.

matteo.pelle.pellegrino@gmail.com



+39 349 213 5002



Milan, Italy



matteopellegrino.dev



github.com/arabello



linkedin.com/in/mttpll/

## **Experience**

Software Engineer Full Stack: Typescript, React, Go, Node, Scala, functional programming. Mar 2021 - present DevOps: Kubernetes, Docker, Terraform, AWS. buildo srl, Milan, Italy Requirements Gathering and Discovery. May 2023 - Present Al assisted tools ownership: I am responsible to facilitate the company internal usage and improvement of Al-enabled tools. Full-stack development of a platform to interface with and manage Excel models. May 2023 - Present Scala Typescript React Design System End-to-end development of Al-based Conversational Intelligence product features for Feb 2023 - May 2023 online meetings video recording, including requirements gathering, design, and full-stack implementation. Go HTMX AWS Terraform AI Prompt Engineering "Know Your Customer" backend service and client Typescript SDK (Vanilla + React) Sep 2022 - Feb 2023 federating multiple Identity Providers Go OpenAPI Docker Typescript React Apr 2022 - Sep 2022 International-team design and implementation of a multi-region and multi-tenant PaaS solution for developing and deploying cloud-native applications. · Inner and Outer loop platform services developing • IAM Service integration federating external Identity Providers Kubernetes OIDC OAuth2 DevSecOps tools Docker Jan - Mar 2022 Discovery and design analysis of an R&D medical standalone software Electron Requirements Gathering Discovery Analysis Nov 2021 - Jan 2022 Open ID Connect-based authentication system design and PoC implementation to federate external Identity Providers for a multi-tenant cloud app. Node OIDC OAuth2 Kubernetes React Oct 2021 - Mar 2022 Internal open-source project maintenance: formo, a type-safe React form state management library. Typescript React Mar - Nov 2021 International-team development of a large bank frontend application involving complex user flows and a custom Design System.

**Machine Learning & Computer Vision Intern**  Synthetic image generation/augmentation API development. Design and implementation of an SDK to generate and manage artificial datasets with containerized deployment

Matteo Pellegrino 1

Typescript React

Jan 2020 - Jul 2020 Datalogic USA Pasadena, California Python OpenCV Docker

Full-stack Developer

Intern

Jul 2014 - Sep 2014 Multitraccia SC Reggio Emilia, Italy Development of an appointment scheduling application as a summer internship.

PHP

#### **Education**

**Master of Computer Engineering** 

University of Bologna

2018-2021

110/110 cum laude

Bachelor of Computer Engineering

University of Bologna

2015-2018 104/110 **IT Upper-secondary Diploma** 

I.I.S. Blaise Pascal 2010-2015

100/100 cum laude

## Languages

**Italian** Native Speaker

English Professional working proficiency IELTS Academic 7.0 (CEFR C1)

### **Miscellaneous**

**Espanso Hub** 

Nov 2021 - present

<u>Espanso</u> is a privacy-first cross-platform text expander. I'm the creator and maintainer of <u>Espanso Hub</u> the official web application, built using <u>Nextjs ssc</u> technology, to search and explore Espanso packages.

https://hub.espanso.org/

Dokey

Nov 2017 - Feb 2019

Dokey is a productivity app for professionals. The project was involved in the startup program of <u>AlmaCube</u> incubator in Bologna. During this experience I learned about the <u>startup environment and lean approach</u>, enforced my <u>Android/Kotlin skills</u> and took care of the platform and brand <u>UI/UX design</u>.

https://www.matteopellegrino.me/dokey-web

**HN Read Time** 

Nov 2019

Chrome extension showing read time preview of <u>Hacker News</u> articles. Being a constant HN reader, I built this tool to immediately know how much time an article will take to be

read. I also got the opportunity to learn more about web scraping.

https://www.matteopellegrino.me/dokey-web

SAM Feb 2019 Scala source code scraper aimed to retrieve module-level metrics based on the  ${\color{blue}\textbf{Clean}}$ 

Architecture concepts from the homonymous book by Robert Martin.

https://github.com/arabello/sam

**KSLL** 

Apr 2018 - Jul 2018

<u>Bachelor's degree thesis</u>: design and development of an <u>Android module</u> to dynamically download and run Android/Kotlin code with digital signature checking at runtime.

2018- 2019

I took part upon selection to the University of Bologna Startup Incubator.

2019

L took part upon selection to the event "E-Factor. The Ferrari Case Study.

I took part upon selection to the event "F-Factor: The Ferrari Case Study".
 Lectures of an Android programming course at my upper-secondary school.

2016 - 2017 Organizer at the Reggio Emilia Google Developers Group community.

Matteo Pellegrino 2